holidaylettings.co.uk 2018-09-02

# TripAdvisor Holiday Rentals

This document sets out the basis on which any personal data we collect from you, or that you provide to us, will be processed by us. By using our website (“ **Website** ” or “ **site** ”), you indicate that you accept this Privacy Policy. Please do not use our site if you do not agree to this Privacy Policy.

Holiday Lettings Limited (" **we** ", " **us** ") is registered in England and Wales, Company registration number: 5282912. Our registered office is: 7 Soho Square, London, W1D 3QB, UK. We treat the personal data of site users with the utmost respect and confidentiality and take reasonable steps to ensure that your personal data is stored securely and accurately.

In general, we use the personal data we collect about you to help our advertisers provide accommodation solutions to users of our site, provide information services to relevant third parties, improve the features and services we offer and support our own marketing and promotion efforts.

By accessing our Website and utilising our services, you acknowledge that you have read and understood this Privacy Policy and the information collection and handling practices outlined in it.

We may change this Privacy Policy from time to time so please check back regularly to keep informed of any updates. 

This Privacy Policy was last updated on 25th May, 2018.

**Overview**

This Privacy Policy describes in detail our policy and practices regarding our collection, use and disclosure of your personal data.

We understand that providing information online involves a great deal of trust on your part. We take this trust very seriously, and make it a high priority to ensure the security and confidentiality of the personal data you provide us with when you visit our Website or use our services.

  1. Collection of your personal data
  2. How we use your personal data
  3. With whom we share your personal data
  4. How long we keep your personal data
  5. Cookies and other web technologies
  6. Your rights
  7. How we protect your personal data
  8. External links
  9. International transfers
  10. Changes to this Privacy Policy
  11. How you can contact us

  1. **Collection of your personal data**

Personal data means any information about an individual from which that person can be identified, such as your first and last name, telephone number, postal and electronic addresses, date of birth, password, and payment information. It does not include data where the identity has been removed (anonymous data).

In the course of our business, we collect and process personal data in different ways. We may collect personal data you give us directly but we also collect data by logging how you interact with our services, for example by using cookies on this Website. We may also receive information from third parties.

The personal data we collect about you may include, but is not limited to: your name, email address, postal address, phone number, billing information, survey responses, booking details and other information you may provide about yourself to our site, such as your IP address and web browser software. 

You can choose not to provide this personal data to us, but in general some personal data is required in order for you to receive relevant offerings from Holiday Lettings and its partners and enjoy other benefits of being a user of the Website; make rental property bookings or participate in a survey, promotion or contest. In addition, some information is also required in order for you to ask us a question or initiate other transactions on our site.

  * **Information that you provide us with:** We receive and store any information you enter on our Website or give us in any other way.

  * **Automatic Collection of Information** : We automatically collect some information from your computer or device when you visit the Website. For example, we collect your session data, including your IP address, the navigation software used and the reference site. We may also collect information about your online activity, such as reviewed content, pages visited and bookings. We automatically collect this type of information to try to better understand your interests and preferences and to better personalise your

  2. **How we use your personal data**

We only use the personal data that we collect about you for specific purposes.

This includes, but is not limited to, to offer our services to you, including your access to and use of our website and to publish your reviews, ratings and photos, communicate with you about your account or use of our site and services, respond to, or following up on, your comments and questions, and otherwise provide customer service, notify you about changes to our terms or privacy policy, ask you to leave a review or take a survey, operate and improve our site and services, personalise your experience on our site, measure interest in and improve our site and services, notify you about promotions and special offers, to let you partake in a prize draw, competition or complete a survey, protect, investigate and deter against fraudulent, unauthorised or illegal activity, administer and protect our business and to resolve disputes or troubleshoot problems.

We will only use your personal data when the law allows us to. Most commonly, we will use your personal data in the following circumstances:

  * Where we need to perform the contract we are about to enter into or have entered into with you.
  * Where it is necessary for our legitimate interests (or those of a third party) and your interests and fundamental rights do not override those interests.
  * With your consent.
  * Where we need to comply with a legal or regulatory obligation.

**Marketing**

We want to make it easy for you to take advantage of travel-related opportunities on our Website. One way we do this is by sending you emails that contain information about your travel-related interests. We believe these emails will provide you with useful information about travel-related special offers available through our sites

You will receive marketing messages from us if you have given your consent, if you have requested them or if you purchased services from us and you have not opted out of receiving marketing messages.

Each time you receive an email of this type, you will be able to tell us if you no longer wish to receive them, or deny push notifications in the application, or change the settings of your mobile device to do so. You will be able to unsubscribe from marketing communications at any time by clicking on the unsubscribe link that you will find at the bottom of each communication you receive from us.

Please note that we may continue to send you service communications, such as administrative messages about your account or transactional messages related to one of your bookings or your Holiday Lettings account. It is not possible to unsubscribe from these service communications.

  3. **With whom we share your personal data**

Holiday Lettings may share your information with other parties, including other group companies and third parties listed below. If we sell or divest our business or any part of it, and your personal data relates to such sold or divested part of our business, or if we merge with another business, we will share your personal data with the new owner of the business or our merger partner, respectively. If we are legally obliged to do so, we will share personal data to protect our customers, the site, as well as our company and our rights and property.

  * _Suppliers_ including, but not limited to, property managers or owners who fulfil travel bookings, and third party providers of other services such as photography (if such services are made available from time to time, and you choose to avail of them). Throughout the Website and its affiliated sites, all products and services provided by third party suppliers are described as such. Please note that these suppliers may also contact you as necessary to obtain additional information about you or your travel plans, to facilitate travel reservations or bookings or for other purposes consistent with the practices described in their privacy policies and terms of use.
  * _Payment solution providers_ (if you use such payment solution providers), whereby you agree that we may share data about you with the payment solution provider and vice versa in order to facilitate or assess your use of the online payment platform or for other internal purposes. Such data may include details of enquiries, bookings, transactions, refunds, chargebacks or other claims or events relating to advertisements and/or payments.
  * _Third party vendors_ who provide services or functions on our behalf, including business analytics, payment processing, customer service, marketing, public relations, distribution of surveys or promotions and fraud prevention. We may also authorise third party vendors to collect information on our behalf, including, for example, as necessary to operate features of our Website or to facilitate the delivery of online advertising tailored to your interests. Third party vendors have access to and may collect information only as needed to perform their functions and are not permitted to share or use the information for any other purpose.
  * _Business partners_ with whom we may offer products or services in conjunction, or whose products or services we think may be of interest to you. You can tell when a third party is involved in a product or service you have requested because their name will appear either with ours or separately. If you choose to access these optional services, we may share information about you, including your personal data, with those partners. Please note that we do not control the privacy practices of these third party business partners.
  * _Companies within our corporate family._ We may share your personal data within the TripAdvisor group of companies, as well as with our parent companies and domestic and international corporate affiliate companies and websites. This sharing enables us to provide you with information about products and services (both travel-related and other) which we think might interest you, and to facilitate rental bookings. To the extent that our parent company and corporate affiliates have access to your personal data, they will follow practices that are at least as restrictive as the practices described in this Privacy Policy. They also will comply with applicable laws governing the transmission of promotional communications and, at a minimum, give you an opportunity in any commercial email they send to choose not to receive such email messages in the future.

We may also share your information if we believe, in our sole discretion, that such disclosure is necessary:

  * to comply with legitimate and enforceable subpoenas, court orders or other legal process; to establish or exercise our legal rights; to defend against legal claims or as otherwise required by law. In such cases, we reserve the right to raise or waive any legal objection or right available to us.
  * to investigate, prevent or take action regarding illegal or suspected illegal activities; to protect and defend the rights, property or safety of Holiday Lettings, our customers or others and in connection with our Owner and Traveller Terms of Use and other agreements.
  * In connection with a corporate transaction, such as a divestiture, merger, consolidation or asset sale, or in the unlikely event of bankruptcy.

We also may share aggregate or anonymous information with third parties, including advertisers and investors. For example, we may tell our advertisers the number of visitors our Website receives or the most popular holiday destinations. This information does not contain any personal data and is used to develop content and services we hope you will find of interest.

  4. **How Long We Keep Your Personal Data**

We will only retain your personal data for as long as necessary to fulfil the purposes we collected it for, including for the purposes of satisfying any legal, accounting or reporting requirements.

To determine the appropriate retention period for personal data, we consider the amount, nature and sensitivity of the personal data, the potential risk of harm from unauthorised use or disclosure or your personal data, the purposes for which we process your personal data and whether we can achieve those purposes through other means and the applicable legal requirements.

  5. **_Cookies and other web technologies_**

We collect information via cookies and other similar technologies. Cookies are small text files that are automatically placed on your computer or mobile device when you visit a website. Cookies contain basic information about your use of the internet. Your browser resends these cookies to our site each time you visit it so that your computer or mobile device is recognised in order to personalise and enhance your browsing experience. 

Like many websites, we use "cookies" to enable us to personalise your visits to our site, simplify the signing in procedure, keep track of your preferences and to track the usage of our Website.

You can find out more detailed information in our Cookie Policy.

Data collected to serve you with relevant advertising

Holiday Lettings is committed to providing you with relevant content and information across our sites. To do this, we may collect information about your travel-related searches and other site activities and use this information to serve you with ads on our sites or elsewhere online that match your interests. We may share this information with affiliated third parties so they can serve you with advertisements.

Data collected by business partners and ad networks to disseminate targeted advertisements

Many of the advertisements you see on the TripAdvisor family of sites are served by a company in the TripAdvisor group or one of its service providers. But we also allow third parties to collect information about your online activities through cookies and other technologies. The information gathered by these third parties is used to make predictions about your characteristics, interests or preferences and to display advertisements on our sites and across the Internet tailored to your interests.

  * Please note that we do not have access to or control over cookies or other technologies these third parties may use to collect information about your interests, and the information practices of these third parties are not covered by this Privacy Policy.

Your browser will have the option to prevent websites using cookies (your browser's help screen or manual will tell you how to do this), but please note that this may reduce the functionality of our site and other websites.

Like all websites, our servers automatically record "log files" containing information about the volume and characteristics of our Website traffic, for example IP address, numbers of pages viewed, length of time spent on site. We use log files to build pictures of how our site is used, which help us to monitor and improve the service. We cannot identify you from your log files alone. 

  6. **Your rights**

You can check, supplement and update the information you have provided us with or change your marketing preferences by sending a request to us using the Help Centre or the contact details provided below.

In accordance with applicable law, you also have the right of access, the right of rectification, the right to erasure, the right to the restriction of processing, the right to data portability and the right to object. Please find below more details and information on how and when you can exercise your rights. We will respond to your request within one month, but have the right to extend this period with for an additional two months.

You have the following rights with regard to your personal data:

  * The right to request access to your personal data. This enables you to receive a copy of the personal data we hold about you and to check that we are lawfully processing it.

  * The right to request to correct your data if they are inaccurate. You may also supplement any incomplete data we have, taking into account the purposes of the processing.

  * The right to request deletion of your personal data if:

    * your personal data is no longer necessary for the purposes for which we collected or processed it; or

    * you withdraw your consent if the processing of your personal data is based on consent and no other legal ground exists; or
    * you object to the processing of your personal data and we do not have an overriding legitimate ground for processing; or
    * your personal data is unlawfully processed; or
    * your personal data has to be deleted for compliance with a legal obligation.

  * The right to object to the processing of your personal data. We will comply with your request, unless we have a compelling overriding legitimate interest for processing or we need to continue processing your personal data to establish, exercise or defend a legal claim.
  * The right to restrict the processing of personal data, if:

    * the accuracy of your personal data is contested by you, for the period in which we have to verify the accuracy of the personal data; or
    * the processing is unlawful and you oppose the deletion of your personal data and request restriction; or
    * we no longer need your personal data for the purposes of processing, but your personal data is required by you for legal claims; or
    * you have objected to the processing, for the period in which we have to verify overriding legitimate grounds.

  * The right to data portability. You may make a request that we receive your personal data that we record on our systems. You may also request that we send this personal data to a third party, where feasible. You only have this right if it regards personal data you have provided us with, the processing is based on consent or necessary for the performance of a contract between you and us or the processing is done by automated means.

You can exercise your rights by contacting us using the methods stipulated below.

You will not have to pay a fee to access your personal data (or to exercise any of the other rights). However, we may charge a reasonable fee if your request is clearly unfounded, repetitive or excessive.

We may need to request specific information from you to help us confirm your identity and verify your right to access your personal data (or to exercise any of your other rights). This is a security measure to ensure that personal data is not disclosed to any person who has no right to receive it. We may also contact you to ask you for further information in relation to your request to speed up our response.

  7. **_How  we protect your personal data_**

We want you to feel confident about using the Website to plan and book your holiday rental, so we are committed to protecting the information we collect. While no website can guarantee security, we have implemented and maintain appropriate physical, administrative, technical and organisational measures to protect the personal data you provide us against unauthorised or unlawful access, use or disclosure and against accidental loss, damage, alteration or destruction.

For example, only authorised employees are permitted to access personal data, and they only may do so for permitted business functions.

  8. **External  links**

Our Website may include links to third party websites, plug-ins and applications. If you access other websites from the links provided on our Website, the operators of those websites may collect information from you, which will be used by them in accordance with their Privacy Policy, which may differ from our Privacy Policy. We do not control these third party websites and recommend that you examine the privacy statements posted on those other websites to understand their procedures for collecting, using and disclosing personal data.

  9. **International transfers**

Your personal data may be transferred to other countries for the purposes described in this Privacy Policy. When we transfer your personal data outside the European Economic Area, we take the following precautions to ensure that your personal data is properly protected.

Whenever we store or transfer your personal data outside the European Economic Area, we will do so in accordance with applicable law and we will ensure a similar degree of protection is afforded to it by implementing appropriate safeguards. Transfers of personal data are made:

  * to a country recognised by the European Commission as providing an adequate level of protection, or;
  * to a country which does not offer adequate protection but whose transfer has been governed by the standard contractual clauses of the European Commission or by implementing other appropriate cross-border transfer solutions to provide adequate protection.

By using our services, you understand that your information may be transferred to our facilities and those third parties with whom we share it as described in this Privacy Policy.

  10. **Changes to this Privacy Policy**

Holiday Lettings may change, update and/or replace this Privacy Policy from time to time. We will note the date that revisions were last made to this Privacy Policy on the first page of this Privacy Policy, and any revisions will take effect upon posting. We will notify our users of any material changes to this Privacy Policy by sending a notification to the email address you have given us or by posting a notice on our site. We encourage you to check this Privacy Policy from time to time to review the most current version.

  11. **How  you can contact us**

If you have any questions or complaints about the processing of your personal data by us, please contact us using our contact form: <https://help.holidaylettings.co.uk/contact_form>. You also have the right to lodge a complaint to the supervisory authority about the way we process your personal data. We would, however, appreciate the chance to deal with your concerns before you approach the supervisory authority, so please contact us in the first instance.

Our full details are:

Holiday Lettings Limited, 7 Soho Square, London, W1D 3QB, England.

Attn: Privacy/Legal Department

If you contact us by phone, the conversations may be recorded. You will be notified of these recordings at the beginning of the call. We use these recordings to improve the quality or compliance of our customer service, to verify the accuracy of the information you provide, to ensure prevention of fraud and to train our teams. We keep these recordings for as long as necessary, and then erase them. Your personal data collected during a call is processed in accordance with the provisions of this Privacy Policy.

Last updated: 08 August 2018
